请问现在为何都用小灯泡？ 我记得以前都用大灯泡
Why is everybody using these tiny,little lights nowadays?I remember when people used big ones.
真是个很久远的故事了，爷爷
That's a good story,Grandpa.
莫妮卡居然让别人布置她的圣诞树 谁又把她灌醉了吗？
Wow. Monica's letting other people help decorate her tree?Did someone get her drunk again,or...?
圣诞节的意义不在于圣诞树 而在于与所爱的人共度
Having a perfect tree is not what Christmas is about.It's about being with loved ones.
说得真好，布置好了
That is nice. And we're done. Ta-da!
我总觉得它少了一股圣诞味
It just doesn't quite feel like Christmas to me.
那这样呢
Oh,here.
这样才像圣诞节
See,now it feels like Christmas.
本集播出：“招牌舞”
The One With The Routine
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
这就是犹太陀螺的由来
And that's the story of the dreidel.
有些人说圣诞树源自古埃及
Some people trace the Christmas tree to the Egyptians...
在每年白昼最短的日子 他们会把棕榈枝带进屋里
who'd bring palm branches into huts on the shortest day of the year...
象征生命战胜死亡
symbolizing life's triumph over death.
那是4千年前的事了
And that was,like,4000 years ago.
你开始讲这个故事也差不多是那时候
Around the same time that you started this story.
你们好
-Hey,you guys.
乔伊，怎么了
-Hey. What's up?
我不出门不行
I had to get out of the apartment.
吉宁到处做伸展运动
Janine's stretching all over.
一转头就看到她在…
Everywhere I look she's like....
难怪你无法抗拒
I can see why that's hard to resist.
我好喜欢她
I like her so much.
可惜她对你没感觉 就是啊，她好可爱
I'm sorry she doesn't feel the same.I know. And she's so sweet.
我好想喂她吃葡萄 帮她梳头
I just want to feed her grapes and brush her hair.
你知道她不是猴子吧？
You are aware that she's not a monkey,right?
我已经不在乎吉宁了
I am so over Janine.
我原本觉得她很火辣 现在她已经成了过去式
Yeah,at first I thought she was hot,but now she's like old news.
你们好 吉宁
-Hey,guys. -Janine!
我刚接到除夕特别节目的通告
I'm gonna be a dancer on a TV special for New Year's Eve.
叫什么狄克摇滚狄奇之夜的
It's called some sort of Dickin' Rockin' Dicky Eve.
慢着
Hold it.
是狄克克拉克新年摇滚之夜吗 就是那个
Are you talking about Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve?Yeah,that's what I said.
天哪，我们爱死那个节目了
Oh,my God,we love that show!
从我有记忆以来 罗斯和我每年都看
Ross and I have been watching it since I can remember.
内心深处的你仍是个小胖妹
You're still just a little fat girl inside,aren't you?
我今年要去当狂欢派对来宾
I'm gonna be one of the party people.
你要去当派对来宾？ 那些人最酷了
You're gonna be a party person? Those guys rock the most!
他们叫我带人去 你愿意当我的舞伴吗？
They said to bring someone. Want to be my dance partner?
当然，我很愿意跟你渡过新年
I would love to spend New Year's with you.
明天就要录影了，我也不太懂为什么
They're taping tomorrow. I don't understand why..
是这样的 时代广场的部分是现场直播
Well,how it works is...the part with Dick Clark in Times Square is actually live.
但他们会预录狂欢派对的画面 知道这一点的人并不多
But they tape some of the party stuff ahead of time.Not a lot of people know that.
你们也想去吗？
Do you guys want to come too?
真的还假的？ 一言为定
-Are you serious? -We are there!
你笑什么笑？
What are you laughing at?
我跟他交往是过去式了 但你还跟她在一起
Well,I used to date him,but you're still going out with her.
谢谢…那我们就一起去
Thanks. Great,so we can all go together.
我得走了，回头见
I gotta run. I'll catch you later.
再见 吉宁再见
Bye,Janine.
她是不是约我了？
Did she just ask me out on a date?
应该不是
I don't think so.
她找他参加 千禧年最盛大的晚会耶
She invited him to the biggest party of the millennium.
但她也找了你和罗斯
Yeah,but she also invited you and Ross.
很抱歉，那应该不算约会
I'm sorry,I don't think that that was a romantic thing.
或许吧，但我有一个办法
Well,maybe. But,hey,I know how I can find out.
我们不是要参加跨年晚会？
It's a New Year's Eve party.
到了午夜，我可以亲她
So at midnight,I can kiss her.
要是她也回吻，太棒了
And if she kisses me back,great.
要是她说“你干什么？”
If she says,"What are you doing?"
我就说“都是新年害的”
I can say,"lt wasn't me,it was New Year's."
比高中时罗斯想亲我的借口要好 他说他需要润唇膏
That's better than Ross kissing me in high school and saying that he did it because he needed Chap Stick.
那天很干燥
It was a dry day.
我们要上狄克克拉克跨年晚会 我的天哪
We are going to Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve!Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
我的天啊
听着，我录过影，我有些建议
Okay,I've been on sets before...so let me give you some advice.
虽然是上电视，我们只管跳舞
It's a show,but we're just dancing.
没什么大不了的 最重要的是要酷
It's no big deal.Important thing to remember: Stay cool.
了解
-Got it. -Okay.
天哪，跟我梦想的一样
Oh,my God! It's just like I dreamed it!
全体集合
Everyone! Gather up!
借过
-Excuse us! -Excuse us!
我们要做的是
Here's what's gonna happen
音乐一放，你们就跳舞 我们会录影，你们不要看镜头
The music's gonna start,you're gonna dance...we'll tape it. Don't look at the camera.
有问题吗？
Questions?
我有，什么时候播出？
Yeah,I have a question. When is this gonna air?
好，你们去那边跳 你们去那边跳
Yeah. Now,you guys dance over there...you guys,over there.
你们两个在这里，其他人散开
I want you two here.Everyone else,spread out.
我们最好不要配一对 因为我们是兄妹
We'd rather not dance together because we're brother and sister.
对，那样会有点怪
Yeah,it would seem kind of weird.
会比大老远跑来 却得立刻滚回家来得怪吗？
As weird as coming all the way down here and then having to go home right now?
罗斯…所以是什么时候播？
So when is it gonna air?
你找厨房，我找后面的柜子
You look in the kitchen,I got the closet.
不必浪费时间了，我在这里
I can save you time,ladies. I'm right here.
钱德，你出去一下 这件事与你无关
Yeah. Why don't you take a walk? This doesn't concern you.
我们在找莫妮卡送的圣诞礼物
We're looking for our presents from Monica.
什么？太差劲了 不会，我们每年都找
That's terrible.No,we do it every year.
那就不差劲了
Oh,well,that makes it not terrible.
但我们没有找到过 她老是打败我们，奸诈的贱人
Yeah,we never find them.She's always bested us,that wily...minx.
放心，我们找1个小时 就会到乔伊那边找，好吗？
We'll search here for an hour...and then we'll go to Joey's and search,okay?
不好，你们不能找她送的礼物
-You can't look for Monica's presents.
我们一定要找
-We have to.
你们不一定要找，也不能找 因为我也住在这里
You don't have to. And you can't,because I live here too.
那你应该跟我们一起找
Well,then you should look with us.
为什么？
Why?
你都不愁要送莫妮卡什么吗？ 不会，我有个很棒的构想
Aren't you worried about what to get Monica?No,I have a great idea for her present.
就只有很棒的构想？
Oh,that's it? A great idea? Oh,yeah?
那样是不够的
That's not enough
要是她送你一个大礼 两个普通礼和一堆小礼呢？
What if she gets you a great present two mediums and lots of little ones
而你只送她一份礼 她一定会很难过
and you just get her one present? She'll feel bad.
你为什么要让她难过？ 为什么？为什么？
Why would you do that to her? Why? Why?
有我帮忙找得更快 没错
-If I help,we can find them faster! -Right!
找到一个了 是梅西百货的袋子
We have a live one!-Oh,it's a Macy's bag!
这是给谁的？
Who's it for?
亲爱的失败者 你们真以为我会藏在沙发下？
"Dear losers,do you really think I'd hide presents under the couch?
附注：钱德，我就知道你会让步
P.S. Chandler,I knew they'd break you."
她可能已经发现了
Uh-oh. She may be onto us.
我们今年一定要找到
We are so gonna find them this year.
你们刚才说会到对面去找 该不会是每年都去吧？
You said you'd go across the hall and look. Do you do that every year?
是啊
Yeah.
你们没有到我的柜子里面 翻我的健身袋底下吧？
You don't go into the back of my closet...and look under my gym bag or anything?
没有，从来没有
-No. Never do that. -No.
乔伊会托我保管东西 我看都没看过
That's where Joey gave me stuff to store that I've never seen.
刚才的事是幻觉
Okay,that did not just happen.
又有摄影机来了
Here comes a camera.
好，小意思，放轻松
Right. No biggie. Stay loose.
他们为什么一直避开？
Why do they keep doing that?
想上镜头就得上那些平台
We have to get up on one of those platforms.
他们一直拍平台上的人 没错
They've been taping them all day.Right.
你们为什么能上去？
What'd you guys do to get up on there?
我们有练过
We learned how to dance.
你练舞时也忘了穿内裤吗？
When you learned to dance,did you forget how to put on underpants?Yeah!
你跳得很好嘛 是吗？
-Hey,you're a good dancer. -Really?
臀部再放松一点会更好
You'd be better if you loosened your hips.
怎么做？ 像这样
-What do you mean? -Like this.
就是这样，跟着节奏摆动 好多了
That's it. Feel the rhythm. That's better.
你去跟那个女生跳
You're dancing with her.
不，我们是一起来的
-We're together. -Yeah,we came together.
我看不出来
I don't see it.
你去跟那个高个子跳 高个子，举手
You are dancing with the tall guy. Tall guy,raise your hand!
不…老兄，拜托让我跟她跳 我很喜欢她，我觉得我有机会
Hey,buddy. Let me dance with her. I like her,and I think I have a shot.
你觉得有？我觉得没有
Really,you think so? I don't.
乔伊那里什么都没…
I couldn't find anything.. Hey,wait!
我们找到了 在客房衣橱的外套后面
Yeah,we found them.They were in the guest-room closet.
你不必担心了，都是些烂东西
You have nothing to worry about because they're crap.
那是我要送给你们的礼物
Those are mine. I got those for you.
谢了，好棒喔
Oh. Thanks,Chandler,they're great!
这个奇怪的金属AZ是什么
Chandler,what is this very weird metal A-Z thing?
那是书挡，是很棒的礼物
Those are bookends. That's a great gift.
好，抱歉，谢谢你送的AZ （音近屁股ass）
Oh. Okay,I'm sorry. Thank you for my "az."
记得放回衣柜里，好吗？
Make sure you put all that stuff back in the closet.
好…对了，你人真好 都搬家了还帮乔伊保管东西
Yes,okay.By the way,I think it's really nice of you that even after you moved you still keep storing that stuff for Joey
喂，舞女
Hey,dancing girl?
我想上厕所
Can I go to the bathroom?
来转一下
Here we go.
好了
Yeah.
很不错喔，盖勒兄妹
Looking good,Gellers!
还用你说
We know!
你看那个傲慢的家伙，他专门指定上平台的人
That snippy guy's the one who decides who gets on the platform.
我们应该去他面前跳 好
-We should go dance by him. -Okay.
全部暂停
Okay,everybody,hold!
接下来的平台舞者有…
Next on the platforms are....
你们两个，还有…
You two! And....
你们两个
-You two! -Cool!
请问一下
Excuse me,sir?
如果我不穿内裤会入选吗？ 莫妮卡
Would it help if I weren't wearing underpants?Monica!
会吗？
Would it?
那我不穿呢？
How about me?
高个子
Hey,tall guy!
我想跟你聊聊你的舞伴
I want to talk to you about that girl you're dancing with.
她真不赖，我还差点带老婆来
She's nice,huh? To think I almost brought my wife to this.
是啊…好
Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
老兄，我和她是一起来的 我想在新年倒数时吻她，我想追她
Look,I came with that girl,okay?I plan to kiss her at the New Year's countdown.I'm trying to win her over.
所以能不能… 不行
I..I don't think so.
拜托啦，你可以跟我的舞伴跳 她跳得很“西瓜”
You can dance with my partner.She's real mellow.
你在跟这个女生交往吗？
Look,you dating this girl you came with?
我希望过了今晚可以…
I was hoping after tonight that maybe I could....
那就是公平竞争，抱歉
No. No. She's fair game if you ask me. Sorry,buddy.
好吧，公平竞争 你说得对，我还能说什么
All right. Hey.Fair is fair. When you're right,you're right. What can I say?
你是小学生吗？
Are you in second grade?
尿裤子的是你
Hey,man,you're the one who wet his pants.
莫妮卡不会把礼物藏在这里的
Monica would not hide the presents down here.
怎么不会 我一直想要一个老嬉皮
No,but she did. Look,there's that old hippie I've always wanted.
要是藏在这里，甘瑟一定知道
If they are here,Gunther knows about it.
我可以去套他，他很喜欢我
And I could get it out of him. He's had a huge crush on me.
这样利用他不公平，还是你去 好
That's not fair to play with his head,though. You do it.Okay.
甘瑟
Hey,Gunther.
圣诞佳节又要来了
Hi.Getting to be that holiday time again,huh?
圣诞节确实很神奇
Yes,it's like a miracle.
我想说既然到了送礼的季节
I was thinking,since it's the time of giving gifts...
不知道这里有没有我的礼物？ 你懂我的意思吧
I was wondering,are there any presents around here for me?You know what I mean?
我找到了 那是要捐出去的玩具
-I think I found them. -That's the Toys for Tots collection bin.
很方便不是吗？ 对捐赠单位来说
-That's awfully convenient,don't you think? -For the tots it is.
你们猜怎样？ 你找到了吗？
-Hey,you guys,guess what. -Did you find them?
不是，甘瑟昏倒了
No,Gunther fainted.
真讨厌
Man,this sucks.
要是被爸妈嫉妒完却没上电视 到时候谁是失败者？
If Mom and Dad don't see us on TV after we made them jealous then who's gonna be the losers then?
我知道怎样可以上平台了 怎样？
I know what'll get us up on a platform.What?
跳招牌舞
The routine!
我们中学毕业后就没跳过了
We haven't done the routine since middle school.
等那个傲慢的家伙看过招牌舞 会帮我们专门搭一座平台的
When the snippy guy sees the routine...he'll want to build us our own platform.
有那么赞吗？
Was it that good?
我们得了兄弟姐妹组的特别奖
We got honorable mention in the brother/sister dance category!
假的午夜快到了，我们还能怎样
It's almost fake midnight. Do we really have any other choice?
那好吧，爸妈会很有面子
Okay,let's do it.Mom and Dad are gonna be so faced!
五六七八
Five,six,seven,eight!
接下来该谁上平台还用问吗？
So do we really need to ask who's going up on the platform next?
不用，你们上去照样再跳一遍
You get up there and do that again,exactly like that.
拍下来当搞笑表演用
Get this. Dick will want it for the Bloopers show.
好了，停
All right,cut!
全体注意，接下来是倒数计时 大家要很兴奋
Listen up,everyone!When we start again,it'll be the countdown...so I want to see everybody's excitement!
限你3秒钟之内离开我的舞伴
Hey,guy!You got three seconds to get away.
怎么了？ 你看他的裤子
What's going on here?Take a look at the guy's pants!
你是叫我们要兴奋 但他也兴奋过头了吧？
You told us to show excitement,but don't you think he went overboard?
你是有什么毛病吗？给我出场 滚啦，湿裤子
What's the matter with you? Go!Yeah,take a hike,wet pants!
你相信吗？
Can you believe this?
进入千禧年时我们会在平台上 我知道
We're on the platform for the millennial moment!I know!
你没有偷练招牌舞吧？ 当然没有
You haven't been practicing the routine,have you?No.
我也有
Me too!
音乐响起来时我想跳机器人舞步
When the music starts...I was thinking about maybe going into the robot.
罗斯 跳招牌舞就好，我们不想看起来像傻瓜
Ross,we should stick to the routine. We don't want to look stupid.
回到现场，倒数10秒 10，9，8，7…
All right,we're back! Ten seconds left.Ten. Nine,eight.Seven.
好，这一刻终于来了 一切顺其自然
-Okay,it all comes down to this.Whatever happens,happens.
命运的安排
Destiny.
3，2，1
three,two,one!
停 不（与“新”谐音）！
-Cut! -No!
…年，“新”年快乐
Year!Happy "No" Year!
接着是时代广场的现场画面 大家辛苦了，收工
Now we go to the live shot of Times Square. That's a wrap!
那个傲慢家伙说什么？
What did that snippy guy say?
他把不跳舞的人赶走了 所以继续跳
I think he's kicking out anyone who's not dancing.So just keep dancing.
看我找到什么 你们好
Hey,look who I found.Oh,hi,guys!
鸟类的方向感很好 或许它们可以帮忙找出礼物
Birds have a very good sense of direction.I thought maybe they could help us find the presents.
如果礼物藏在南方过冬的话
Yes,if the presents are hidden south for the winter.
顺着你的笑话去找也行 你知道在哪里吗？当然不知道
Or we could just follow your clever jokes. Any ideas? Didn't think so.
来，把礼物找出来
Come on,show us where the presents are.
鸭子似乎认为莫妮卡送我垃圾
The duck seems to think that Monica got me garbage.
什么样的回礼能跟垃圾一样好
I wonder what I could get Monica that's as good as garbage.
我的AZ如何？
How about my "az"?
这是空的
-Hey. This is hollow.
什么？ 这排座椅是空心的
-What?This bench,it's hollow.
我居然都不知道
I can't believe I never knew that!
我们的礼物 不！不要直视它们
-Oh,the presents! -Don't look directly at them!
什么？
What?
没事，可以看
All right,no,we could look at them.
这是我的
This one's for me!
这是钱德的，拿去 太好了
This one's for Chandler. Here.
大包的是我的
-And the big one's for me!
赶快拆来看 好
-Oh,let's open them!
等等，我们不能这样
-Wait a minute. We can't do this.
为什么？ 我不想知道莫妮卡送我什么
-Why?-I don't want to know what Monica got me.
她一定很用心的替我找礼物 想给我惊喜，你们这样会坏事
I'm sure she worked hard at getting it and wanting to surprise me.And you guys are gonna ruin that.
我们得把礼物放回去 这样不叫圣诞节
We have to put these back. This is not what Christmas is about.
谁理你，莱纳斯（漫画史努比的主人查理布朗的好朋友）我要拆我的
Whatever,Linus. I'm opening mine.
谁也不准拆
Nobody is opening anything,okay?
我不知道你们怎么想
Look，I don't know about you guys
但我想看莫妮卡 收到礼物的表情
but I want to see the look on her face when I give her my present.
她一定也想看 我收到礼物的表情
I'm sure she wants to see the look on my face when I get mine.
所以求求你们放回去
So,please,please,can we just...? Can we put them back?
你会送我们更好的礼物吗？ 好啦
-Will you get us better gifts? -Fine.
你们好
Hey,guys.
你们找到礼物了？ 钱德，你让她们找到？真好
You found the presents?You let them find the presents?Great.
你知道为你选那个滤水器花了我多久工夫吗？
Do you know how long it took me to find you that water purifier?
你送我滤水器？ 这下我懂了，你的表情真棒
-That's what you got me? -Yes,I see. That look is priceless.
甜蜜的家
Home sweet home,huh?
回到现实真好
Nice to get back to reality.
我们也知道新年会怎样了
Plus,we know how the New Year's gonna go off.
千年虫根本没什么，对吧？
I guess there's no reason for all that Y2K panic,you know?
好吧，晚安
Anyway,good night.
乔伊 怎样？
-Joey? -Yeah?
3，2，1
three,two,one!
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
这是干什么？
What was that for?
今晚当他们喊停 我们没能接吻，我真的很失望
Tonight when they yelled "cut" and we didn't get to kiss...I was really,really disappointed,
我真的…真的很想亲你 真的？
and I just I just really wanted to kiss you.Really?
那时候我也很想亲你…那时候
In the moment,I really wanted to kiss you too. In the moment.
那时候 只有那时候
In the moment. But only in the moment.
你…想再亲一次吗？
So do you want to kiss again?
想啊，离除夕只有2个星期了
Sure. New Year's Eve is only two weeks away.
你能等吗？ 不能
Can you wait?No.
我也是
Me neither.
3，2…
Three,two....
乔伊，不必每次接吻都倒数 好
You don't have to count down every time we kiss.Oh. Okay.
但我觉得我需要几秒钟做准备
Except I sort of felt like I needed a couple seconds to get ready.
我们在平台上 准备带全世界跳进千禧年
We were on the platform,ready to dance into the new millennium...
那家伙却喊了停
and the guy yells,"Cut!"
所以乔伊也没亲到吉宁？ 当然没有
-So Joey didn't get to kiss Janine? -Nope,he sure didn't.
所以你和乔伊还是平分秋色咯
I guess that means that you guys are still tied.
那可不见得 她应该看到我们的招牌舞了
I don't know about that. I think she saw us do our routine.
我用布吉舞步打头阵
I may have boogied right into first place.
等等，你们真的跳了八年级的招牌舞？
So you guys are telling me that you actually did the routine from eighth grade?
对，不过当然得稍做修正
Yeah! But of course we had to update it a little bit.
你反应真快，知道要接住我
Hey,by the way,quick thinking about catching me.
我正想说 你们绝不可能照以前的结尾跳
There's no way you could've done the end...the way you guys did it back then
什么？当然可以
What? We could do it.
不行吧，你以前胖…壮多了
I don't know. You were a lot bigger.. I mean,stronger back then.
我可以，好吗？来吧
I can do it,okay?Come on,let's go! Come on.
一二三四五六七八
One,two,three,four five,six,seven,eight.
我不行
I can't do it!
那样跳就能上电视了
Now,you do that,you're on TV.